Bradley Cornford

Friday, 13 November 2015

Apartment 28, AG1, 1 Furnival Street, Sheffield, South Yorkshire, S1 4QS

T 07866 859 225
E bradcornford@hotmail.co.uk

Objective

To obtain a position that will capitalise on my organisational skills, educational background and technical expertise to develop market leading products and services as part of a team, or individually.

Personal Profile

I am conscientious, self-motivated and analytical with a natural bent for problem solving. I am considered to be an effective communicator with a positive attitude that gets the job done while maintaining my attention to detail. I have strong hands on Microsoft and Open Source web development skills, project planning and customer service experience.

Education and Training

Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield (2007 – 2011)
<u>Degree Subject</u>

BSc Hons Information Technology and Business Studies – First Class

Toll Bar 6th Form, Grimsby (2004 – 2006)A Level Subjects

General Studies, English Language, English Literature, Business Studies

QA, Manchester (2004)

Professional Development

Advanced Microsoft Excel Certification, Advanced Microsoft Access Certification, Standard Crystal Reports Certification

Toll Bar Business & Enterprise College, Grimsby (2000 – 2004)
GCSE Subjects

Applied ICT (Double Award, Applied Business Studies (Double Award), Mathematics, English, English Literature, History, Science (Double Award), Religious Studies, French

Work Experience

Plusnet, Sheffield (2013 - Current)

Senior Software Engineer

Working within one of the internal development teams maintaining and developing existing call centre systems, company external website and sales platforms. My development work has focused on maintaining systems with PHP, PHPUnit, MySQL and using Git for version control. I also maintain Plusnet's internal PHP coding standards closely following PSR standards, and am a member of their peer review guidance committee. As I take more supervisory responsibility for development projects I regularly assume a project planning role utilising the Scrum / Agile project management framework. My most notable achievement is winning an 'Outstanding Achievement' award for resolving our company's website usability issues with content blockers with little to no guidance.

SwitchstancelT, Sheffield (2011 - 2013)

Creative Web Developer

I was a member of the company's web development team and had responsibility for server and client side system developments. These developments comprised a combination of internal case study related proof of concept and client commissioned web based systems. During my final fifteen months I utilised and refined the Time and Project management, business analysis and software development methodologies I was taught at University. As a direct result of honing this skill set I was appointed to the lead development role on one of the company's vertical market products used by the NHS and Universities to publish research project Key Performance Indicators (KPI).

Urban Feather, Scunthorpe (2009 – 2010)

Web Developer

I joined this local company for my degree placement year. One of the company's recently identified strategic objectives was to extend its established brochure web site business to provide more functional e-Commerce and CMS managed internet sites. This was a very successful venture and during my tenure the company secured a number of new clients from a diverse range of business sector, ranging from a large Garden Centre chain to a local wool trading company.

Grimsby Telegraph, Grimsby (2008 – 2009)

Web Designer

I secured this fixed term contract position with the newspapers community portal called ThisisGrimsby. My primary responsibilities were to create and publish news based web pages, Adobe Flash banners and adverts for local businesses. Interestingly enough my limited involvement with this portal provided a valuable insight into the power of social networking as the underlying technology used to support collaborative innovation both within the newspaper business and the wider community.

Skills

With the employer's support I have taught myself a number of development languages such as: HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, ActionScript, Bash and Python. I also possess expert knowledge of development tools such as PHP Storm, Git, Git Flow, Jenkins, Confluence, JIRA, FishEye, Composer, PHPSpec and PHPUnit. Finally I have advanced knowledge of Microsoft Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Visio, and good knowledge of the remaining Microsoft's Office suite.

Adaptability

I relish the prospect of change, not change for changes sake, but as a method of continually improving systems and services. I have always adapted to my environment, whether at university, in employment or on the sports field. Although I seldom analyse my adaptability I am convinced it is the result of continually assessing where I am and what is needed to achieve my next goal.

Effective Communications

During a summer placement I had the opportunity to attend a couple of a company's Corporate Strategy Group meetings as a silent observer. This provided an insight into the manner by which ideas were pitched and sold to Company Directors. This left me with a clear understanding of how important communication skills are. The best idea in the world doesn't sell itself, it has to be sold and competent selling requires a thorough knowledge of the subject being presented and the ability to communicate in the language used by the audience. I regularly put this experience to good use when presenting ideas within the workplace. I have learnt that truly great communication skills are born of confidence and experience and I'm keen to practice and develop both.

Hobbies & Interest

I was once described as a rugby playing geek and to be fair that's a reasonable description. I enjoy playing rugby and was a member of the country champion college Rugby sevens team in 2005. I have also been county Judo champion twice in my later teens. My Judo career stalled spectacularly in 2006 when I broke my thumb playing rugby at a national level and this injury required surgery. Recovering from this bad luck took nearly a year by which time my Judo contemporaries had moved on leaving me with little or no chance of ever making the grade again. I still enjoy participating in just about any sporting activity and actively attend the gym on a daily basis.

References

Sheffield Hallam University

Anita Whitworth 0114 225 4238 Sheffield Hallam University, Howard Street, Sheffield, S1 1WV

SwitchstanceIT

Matt Cuff 0114 286 6366 Electric Works, Sheffield Digital Campus, Sheffield, S1 2BJ